Guide to theGerald Sykes Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Arranged Manuscripts
  - What Kind of World Do Students Face Today? [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 36)
  - Woodlark Montage [short story], (1 t.ms. (assorted drafts)) (Box 36)
  - The Writer and the Psychologist [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - The Yearling Sale [short story], (2 t.ms. (drafts)) (Box 36)
  - The Yearling Sale, (2 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 36)
  - Young Men in the Country [short story], (2 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Young Men in the Country [short story], (2 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Untitled [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Untitled [article of Chester Gilette], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Untitled [short story], (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragment)) (Box 36)
  - Untitled [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 36)
  - Untitled [short story], (1 t.ms. (with carbon copy)) (Box 36)
- Series V: Notes and Notebooks
  - Notes -- file cards & ms. notes (Box 37)
  - Notebooks -- (Commonplace Books), [n.d.] & 1933-1964 (Box 38)
  - Notebooks -- (Commonplace Books), 1965-1980 (Box 39)
  - Notebooks -- (Commonplace Books, projected works A-Z) (Box 40)
  - Notebooks -- (Commonplace Books), 1933-1950 (Box 41)
  - Lecture notebooks, 1954 (Box 41)
- Series VI: Appointment and Address Books
  - Appointment Books, 1928-1984 (Box 42)
  - Address Books (Box 42)
- Series VII: Documents and Photographs
  - Certificate, Navigational Instruction Course, 1921 (Box 43)
  - Certificate, Navigational Instruction Course, 1921 (Box 43)
  - Documents re. Indians (Box 43)
  - Documents re. Metals Reserve Company (Box 43)
  - Documents re. Wartime need for rope (Box 43)
  - Documents re. U.S. Government Office of War Information (Box 43)
  - Documents re. War Production Board - Aluminum (Box 43)
  - Photographs (Box 43)
  - Shaw, Alfred Craig Margaret Rudkin, [n.p.], [n.d.], (9 1/2 x 7 1/2 ins. Photograph, signed on mat) (Box 564)
    [Henry Rudkin was Gerald Sykes' cousin. His wife, Margaret (Peggy), started Pepperidge Farms]
  - Photograph Album (Box 564)
- Series VIII: Ccouse Related Materials
  Within each year, folders arranged by institution and course
  - Course related materials, [v.p.], 1962-1967 (Box 44)
  - Course related materials, [v.p.], 1967-1972 (Box 45)
  - Course related materials, [v.p.], 1972-1975 (Box 46)
  - Course related materials, [v.p.], 1975 & Miscellaneous (Box 47)
- Series IX: Subject Files
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (Box 48)
  - Sykes, Gerald Alienation, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 48)
  - Sykes, Gerald The Center of the Stage, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 48)
  - Sykes, Gerald Children of Light, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 48)
  - Sykes, Gerald Cool Milennium, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 49)
  - Sykes, Gerald Foresights, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 49)
  - Sykes, Gerald Hidden Remnant, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 49)
  - Sykes, Gerald The Nice American, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 49)
  - Sykes, Gerald The Perennial Avant-Garde, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 50)
  - Sykes, Gerald The Price of Technology, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 50)
  - Sykes, Gerald Two Against Thebes, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 50)
  - Sykes, Gerald Unpublished books, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 50)
  - Sykes, Gerald Miscellaneous, ( Documents, printed materials, correspondence) (Box 50)
  - Viereck, Peter Manuscripts & printed materials (Box 50)
- Series X: Printed Materials
  - Printed materials about Sykes (Box 51)
  - Reviews of Sykes' books (Box 51)
  - Offprints inscribed by other authors to Sykes (Box 51)
  - Printed materials about Sykes (Box 52)
  - Books & proofs annotated by Sykes (Box 53)
  - Books by Sykes (Box 54)
  - Books with contributions by Sykes (Box 55)
  - Books and periodicals with contributions by Sykes (Box 56)
- Series XI: Audio Tapes
  - Audio tape cassettes & audio equipment (Box 57)